YYeTs字幕组
翻译  马戏之草
校对  开心想唱草
时间轴  风吹来的那片云
鸣谢  艾伦尔榭
后期  8T
总监  somehacker 草草
女士们先生们 你们等待的一刻终于到来
Ladies and gents, this is the moment you've waited for
黑暗中苦苦寻找 汗水浸透了你脚下的地面
You been searching in the dark, your sweat soaking through the floor
马戏之王
那深入骨头的痒再也无法抑制
And buried in your bones there's an ache that you can't ignore
夺走了你的呼吸 占据了你的思想
Taking your breath, stealing your mind
一切真实都被抛诸脑后
And all that was real is left behind
别再抗拒 它犹如洪流般袭来
Don't fight it, it's coming for you, running at ya
只在乎此刻 不管之后如何
It's only this moment, don't care what comes after
你热烈的美梦步步逼近
Your fever dream, can't you see it getting closer
投降吧 那感觉要让你把持不住
Just surrender 'cause you feel the feeling taking over
它就是火 是自由 是倾泻的洪水
It's fire, it's freedom, it's flooding open
犹如圣坛上的牧师 你会虔诚地信仰
It's the preacher in the pulpit and your blind devotion
你所知的一切在被渐渐瓦解
There's something breaking at the brick of every wall it's holding
告诉我 你可向往那里
All that you know, so tell me do you wanna go?
那被缤纷灯光笼罩的地方
Where it's covered in all the colored lights
那由流浪儿称雄的地方
Where the runaways are running the night
那不可能变为可能的地方 它让你情不自禁
Impossible comes true, it's taking over you
这是最棒的表演
Oh, this is the greatest show
我们点亮夜晚 不肯罢休
We light it up, we won't come down
即使太阳升起也无法阻拦我们
And the sun can't stop us now
看着梦境成为现实 它让你情不自禁
Watching it come true, it's taking over you
这是最棒的表演
Oh, this is the greatest show
这里有你渴望的一切
It's everything you ever want
这里有你需要的一切
It's everything you ever need
全部摆在了你面前
And it's here right in front of you
这里就是你向往的地方
This is where you wanna be (this is where you wanna be)
这里有你渴望的一切
It's everything you ever want
这里有你需要的一切
It's everything you ever need
全部摆在了你面前
And it's here right in front of you
这里就是你向往的地方
This is where you wanna be
这里有你渴望的一切
It's everything you ever want
这里有你需要的一切
It's everything you ever need
全部摆在了你面前
And it's here right in front of you
这里就是你向往的地方
This is where you wanna be
这里有你渴望的一切
It's everything you ever want
这里有你需要的一切
It's everything you ever need
全部摆在了你面前
And it's here right in front of you
我知道 好
I understand, yes.
非常感谢 杰弗里先生 谢谢
Thank you very much, Mr. Jeffrey. Thank you.
今晚之前就能把钱给您
You'll have the money by the end of the day.
我们走
Let's go.
菲尼斯 快走 我们要赶不上火车了
Phineas, hurry up. We are gonna miss the train.
站直了
Stand up straight.
把泥巴擦掉
Wipe that muck off.
翘小指
Pinkie up.
手臂伸展 胳膊肘向外
Arm extended, elbow out.
抿一口 绝不能出声
Sip, and never slurp.
翘小指 手臂伸展
Pinkie in the air, arm extended...
胳膊肘向外
elbow out.
杯子端平 慢慢放下杯子
Keep your cup level. Gently lower your cup.
我们再来一遍吧
Shall we do it again?
翘小指
Pinkie in the air.
手臂伸展 胳膊肘向外 优雅点
Arm extended, elbow out. Gracefully.
夏瑞蒂 过来
Charity, come here.
看你的裙子
Your dress.
我们就把你教成了这样吗
Is this how we've taught you to behave?
都怪我 先生
It's my fault, sir.
是我逗她笑了
I made her laugh.
多谢你的诚实了
Well, thank you for your honesty.
离我女儿远点
Stay away from my daughter.
- 你怎么出来的 - 爬窗
- How did you get out? - The window.
父亲要送我去精修学校
Father is sending me to finishing school.
我不知道我的未来会是什么样
I don't know what my future will be.
我知道
I do.
闭上眼睛 我能看到
I close my eyes and I can see
那等待着我的世界
The world that's waiting up for me
那属于我的世界
That I call my own
穿越黑暗 进入大门
Through the dark, through the door
走过无人曾踏足的地方
Through where no one's been before
这里莫名有种家的感觉
But it feels like home
他们可以说这好像痴人说梦
They can say, they can say it all sounds crazy
他们可以说我只是异想天开
They can say, they can say I've lost my mind
我才不管别人说我痴狂
I don't care, I don't care, so call me crazy
我们可以生活在我们设想的世界之中
We can live in a world that we design
因为每晚当我躺在床上
'Cause every night I lie in bed
脑海中会浮现最缤纷的色彩
The brightest colors fill my head
千万个梦想让我无法入眠
A million dreams are keeping me awake
我想象世界可能变成的样子
I think of what the world could be
我愿景中那美丽的样子
A vision of the one I see
千万个梦想便能实现愿望
A million dreams is all it's gonna take
用千万个梦想构建我们要打造的世界
A million dreams for the world we're gonna make
他们可以说这都是痴人说梦
They can say, they can say it all sounds crazy
- 他们可以说我们只是异想天开 - 别去
- They can say, they can say we've lost our minds - Enough!
夏瑞蒂
Charity!
我才不管别人说我们痴狂
I don't care, I don't care if they call us crazy
我们可以跑去我们所设想的世界
Run away to a world that we design
每晚当我躺在床上
Every night I lie in bed
脑海中会浮现最缤纷的色彩
The brightest colors fill my head
千万个梦想让我无法入眠
A million dreams are keeping me awake
我想象世界可能变成的样子
I think of what the world could be
我愿景中那美丽的样子
A vision of the one I see
千万个梦想便能实现愿望
A million dreams is all it's gonna take
不
No.
用千万个梦想构建我们要打造的世界
A million dreams for the world we're gonna make
看报啊 全世界奇闻轶事
Newspapers. Amazing stories from around the world.
千万个梦想让我无法入眠
A million dreams are keeping me awake
我想象世界可能变成的样子
I think of what the world could be
我愿景中那美丽的样子
A vision of the one I see
千万个梦想便能实现愿望
A million dreams is all it's gonna take
用千万个梦想构建我们要打造的世界
A million dreams for the world we're gonna make
来参加美国铁路建设吧
Come join the Great American Railroad.
一日三餐 包吃包住
Three meals a day. A roof over your head.
薪水公道充足 快来挣钱吧
Fair and ample wages. Come, make your fortune.
去看看美国平原
See the open plains of America.
机会就在铁轨上等着你 先生
Opportunity awaits you sir, out on the rails.
先生 我知道我出身贫寒
Sir I, I know I don't come from much
但我会照顾好你女儿
but I will take care of your daughter
给她跟这一样好的生活
and I will give her a life as grand as this one.
再见 妈妈
Goodbye, mother.
她会回来的
She'll be back.
她迟早会厌倦你那一贫如洗的生活
Sooner or later she will get tired of your life of having nothing
到时她就会回来
and she will keep running back home.
每晚当我躺在床上
Every night I lie in bed
脑海中会浮现最缤纷的色彩
The brightest colors fill my head
千万个梦想让我无法入眠
A million dreams are keeping me awake
我想象世界可能变成的样子
I think of what the world could be
我愿景中那美丽的样子
A vision of the one I see
千万个梦想便能实现愿望
A million dreams is all it's gonna take
用千万个梦想构建我们要打造的世界
A million dreams for the world we're gonna make
不管宏大 还是渺小
However big, however small
都让我参与其中
Let me be part of it all
与你分享梦想
Share your dreams with me
无论成功 或是失败
You may be right, you may be wrong
但求你带我同行
But say that you'll bring me along
去你眼中的世界
To the world you see
去我梦想中的世界
To the world I close my eyes to see
我梦想中的世界
I close my eyes to see
因为每晚当我躺在床上
'Cause every night I lie in bed
脑海中会浮现最缤纷的色彩
The brightest colors fill my head
千万个梦想让我无法入眠
A million dreams are keeping me awake
千万个梦想 千万个梦想
A million dreams, a million dreams
我想象世界可能变成的样子
I think of what the world could be
我愿景中那美丽的样子
A vision of the one I see
千万个梦想便能实现愿望
A million dreams is all it's gonna take
用千万个梦想构建我们要打造的世界
A million dreams for the world we're gonna make
我们要打造的世界
For the world we're gonna make
- 史密斯先生 - 嗯
- Mr. Smith? - Yeah.
- 看看这个 - 是
- Have a look at this? - Of course.
好 我知道了
Yes, yes, I see it.
谢谢 查默斯 这就行了
Thank you, Chalmers, that will do.
先生 我是菲尼斯·泰勒·巴纳姆
Sir. Phineas Taylor Barnum.
恕我冒昧 先生
If I may sir,
我认为凭我的技能和才思
I believe I have skills and ideas...
能做比往加法机里输入数字更重要的工作
that go well beyond counting numbers into an adding machine.
我读到有个德国人 利林塔尔
I have read about this German fellow, Lilienthal...
他研制了一种滑翔机
I believe he's developed a glider
能够载人上天 先生
that could take a man in the air, sir.
那多了不起啊
Isn't that amazing?
如果把这种技术用在这一行里
I mean, if you were to apply that to this business,
那将是革命性的
it would be revolutionary.
先生们 请注意
Gentlemen. Can I have your attention?
你们都被解雇了
You are all dismissed.
破产了
Bankrupt?
公司不还有十几艘商船呢吗
I thought the company had a dozen trading ships.
是啊 葬身中国南海海底了
Yes, at the bottom of the South China Seas.
被台风吹沉了
A typhoon sank them all.
船只登记
- 抓到你了 - 你等着瞧吧
- Tag, you're it! - Oh, you're in for it.
天呐 你回来得可真早
Oh God. You are home early.
而且有新消息之前都不用回去了
And until further notice.
我本来也觉得你不适合那份工作
I didn't think you were along for that job.
看起来我什么工作都不适合
Or any job apparently.
所以我们的生活才那么精彩嘛
That's what makes our life together so exciting.
夏瑞蒂
Charity.
这不是我许诺给你的生活
This isn't the life I promised you.
但我已经有了我想要的一切
But I have everything I want.
- 我说的魔法呢 - 那俩姑娘不是吗
- What about the magic? - What do you call those two girls?
伙计们 看看是谁回来了
Hey, you partners, look who moseyed into the corral.
爸爸
Daddy!
- 过来 - 你带礼物来了吗
- Come here. - Did you bring a present?
什么礼物
Present, for what?
- 我生日的礼物 - 什么
- For my birthday. - Your what?
- 我生日 - 才不是你生日呢
- My birthday. - It's not your birthday.
好吧 我是有件礼物
Okay, I do have a present.
但可不是一般的礼物哦
But not just any present. Oh no.
是史上最棒的生日礼物
The most amazing birthday present ever.
这台了不起的机器原本是
This extraordinary machine was originally
四百年由莱昂纳多·达·芬奇制造的
created by Leonardo Da Vinci 400 years ago.
但它的图纸已经遗失数百年
But the blueprints have been lost for centuries,
直到上周 一个风雨交加的夜晚
until just last week, on a stormy night...
一艘沉没海盗船的残骸冲上了楠塔基特岛的海岸
when a sunken pirate ship washed up on the shores of Nantucket.
人们发现了骸骨和宝藏
They found skeletons and treasures...
而图纸正好
and the blueprints were recovered
被JW商社找回
by none other than JW Mercantile.
图纸只在我手上停留了片刻
The blueprints crossed my desk very briefly...
但我还是把它记了下来
but I managed to commit them to memory...
如果我没有记错
and if I had remembered correctly...
生日快乐 卡罗琳
Happy birthday, Caroline.
这是一台许愿机 你向它许愿
This is a wishing machine. You tell it your wishes...
它会替你守护愿望 直到它成真
and it keeps them safe until they come true.
就算你忘记了 它也永远记得
Even if you forget them, they are always there.
我能许个愿吗
Can I tell a wish?
过来 说吧
Step right up. Go ahead.
我希望...嫁给圣诞老人
I wish to marry Santa Clause.
真是个好愿望
That is a good wish.
我希望...有一双芭蕾舞鞋
I wish for ballet slippers.
这个愿望也很好
Hey, that's a good wish too.
你的愿望呢 妈妈
What is your wish, Mommy?
我希望
I wish...
永远这么幸福
for happiness like this forever.
你 还有你
For you and you...
还有你们爸爸都是
and for your father.
- 没劲 - 没劲
- Boring. - Boring?
幸福怎么没劲了
Since when is happiness ever been boring?
每晚当我躺在床上
Every night I lie in bed
脑海中会浮现最缤纷的色彩
The brightest colors fill my head
千万个梦想让我无法入眠
A million dreams are keeping me awake
我想象世界可能变成的样子
I think of what the world could be
我愿景中那美丽的样子
A vision of the one I see
千万个梦想便能实现愿望
A million dreams is all it's gonna take
用千万个梦想构建我们要打造的世界
A million dreams for the world we're gonna make
金融危机
羊肉价格涨了 猪胸肉就降价了
The goat prices go up, so the pork bellies go down.
查尔斯 我们走
Charles, we're leaving.
这家银行只想借钱给有钱的人
This bank only wants to lend money to people with money.
你看什么 蠢蛋
What are you looking at Flop Doodle?
巴纳姆先生
Mr. Barnum.
你提出的这项投资很有风险 还有些怪异
This venture you propose is risky and somewhat bizarre.
这是十拿九稳的好买卖
It's a good bet, it's what it is.
先生 人们不愿承认
Sir, people don't wanna admit it...
但他们被新奇骇人的东西所吸引
but they are fascinated with the exotic and the macabre.
所以我们喜欢盯着它们看
is why we stare at it.
银行需要高价的抵押品
The bank is going to need substantial collateral.
当然 那是应当的
Of course. I wouldn't suggest otherwise.
这是我商船队的契据和所有权证明
The deed and title to my entire flotilla of trading vessels.
船只登记
银行凭什么要借我们一万美元
Why would a bank loan us 10,000 dollars?
因为我们拿出了抵押品
Because we put up collateral.
但亲爱的 我们没有抵押品啊
But, dear, we don't have any collateral.
当然有 在中国南海
Sure we do. In the South China Seas.
- 在中国南海 - 在中国南海海底
- In the South China Seas? - Deep in the South China Seas.
我们用这笔借款买了什么
And what did we buy with this loan?
巴纳姆美国珍奇博物馆
Barnum's American Museum of Curiosity.
这是什么样的博物馆
What kind of museum is it?
这里犹如一个异世界
A place to be transported.
让人们见识到他们从未见识过的东西
A place where people can see thing they've never seen before.
- 蜡像吗 - 是啊
- Wax figures? - Yeah.
这现在在欧洲最火了 看啊
They are all the rage in Europe. Look.
喉咙疼的玛丽·安托瓦内特
Marie Antoinette with the sore throat.
拿破仑 过来 看
Napoleon. Come here. See?
你能见到一些历史上赫赫有名的人物
You've already met some of the most famous folks from the history.
但也不都是蜡像
But they are not all wax.
这位是伟大的奥马利
This is the Great O'Malley.
妙手大师 幻术大王
Master of sleight of hand, a king of deception.
你不像个魔术师
You don't look like a magician.
我是个小偷
I am a thief.
厉害的小偷 他偷我表时被我抓到了
A very good thief. I caught him nicking my watch.
- 瞧 - 大象
- You see? - An elephant.
不是一般的大象哦
Not just any elephant.
我也可以给你"变"点好东西出来 尽管说
I can get you somethin' real nice. Just say the word.
- 谢了 - 没错 这头10吨的公象
- Thank you. - Oh yeah. Oh, yeah. This is a ten- ton bull
来自非洲平原
straight from the plains of Africa.
看那个
And, look at that.
全世界最高的长颈鹿
The tallest giraffe in the world.
我能爬到它腿上吗
Can I climb up its leg?
绝对不能 好了
Absolutely no. OK.
我知道这差强人意
Now, I know how it looks.
幸好 要不我得担心了
If you didn't, I would be worried.
就是需要收拾收拾
I mean it just needs a little work...
贷款是得每月偿还的
The loan has to be paid back every month.
我们会还的 我们就是需要顾客
Oh yeah, we're gonna pay. We just need customers.
- 上百个 - 会来的
- Hundreds of them. - We're gonna get them.
巴纳姆美国珍奇博物馆
欢迎光临巴纳姆博物馆
Welcome to the Barnum Museum.
只要一小时 先生
It's one hour of your time, sir...
就能改变你的人生
but it will change your life.
我们每小时整点都有表演
We have a shows on the hour, every hour.
我喜欢你的裙子
I love your dress.
胆小的可受不了
Surely not for the faint of heart,
我看得出你肯定喜欢
but I can tell you're gonna love it.
戴帽子的可以半价入场
Half the price for anyone who is wearing a hat.
您走运了 先生
That's you, sir.
欢迎光临巴纳姆博物馆
Welcome to the Barnum Museum.
垃圾
Load of garbage.
欢迎光临巴纳姆博物馆 这里是...
Welcome to the Barnum Museum, where everyone...
卖了几张票
How many tickets?
- 三张 - 三张
- Three. - Three?
家庭开销
爸爸
Daddy.
Daddy?
- 你今天还卖出票了吗 - 卖了几张
- You sell anymore tickets today? - A few. Yeah.
今天周五 大部分人都急着回家
Most of 'em was rushing home, it's Friday.
拇指汤姆历险记
我们卖了几张票
We sold a few.
我觉得是因为你的博物馆里都是死的东西 爸爸
I think you have too many dead things in your museum, daddy.
是吗
Do you?
她说得对 你需要活的东西
She is right. You need something alive.
睡吧 你俩
Go to sleep, both of you.
叹为观止的东西
Something sensational.
- 还会说这么难的词了 - 那是你说的
- That is a big word. - That's your word.
不是实心的东西
Something that isn't stuffed.
- 比如美人鱼 - 或是独角兽
- Like a mermaid. - Or a unicorn.
- 独角兽不是真的 - 美人鱼也不是
- Unicorns aren't real. - Well, mermaids aren't real either.
拇指汤姆历险记
你一定是格特鲁德·斯特拉顿
You must be Gertrude Stratton.
我找你儿子
I am looking for your son.
我没有儿子
I don't have a son.
医院记录可不是这么写的
The hospital record says you do.
叫查尔斯吧 22岁了
Charles, right? Age 22?
查尔斯
Charles.
PT·巴纳姆 为你效劳
P. T Barnum. At your service.
我要组织一场表演
I'm putting together a show
我需要一位明星
and I need a star.
你想让人嘲笑我
You want people to laugh at me.
他们反正也笑你 小伙子 何不挣点钱呢
Well, they are laughing anyway, kid. So, might as well get paid.
我能想象一位士兵 不 将军
I see a soldier. No, a general...
持着剑和枪 骑马飞驰过舞台
riding across the stage with a sword and gun and...
他穿着最精美的军服
and the most beautiful uniform ever made.
世界各地的人们会前来
People will come from all over the world
他们看到他时 不会发出嘲笑
and when they see him they won't laugh.
而是会致敬
They will salute.
征召 奇人异士 大胆表演 世界奇观
怎么样 姑娘们
How is it looking girls?
你在找怪胎吗
You looking for freaks?
我知道哪里有
I know where you can find one of them.
是吗
Really?
来吧 姑娘们
Come on, girls.
- 你好 - 先生 你不该进来的
- Hello. - Sir, you shouldn't be here.
抱歉 是谁在唱歌
I'm sorry. Who is doing that singing?
是你 对吗
It's you, isn't it?
先生 我得请你离开
Sir, I'll have to ask you to leave.
你真是才华横溢 天赋异禀
You are so talented, blessed...
不同凡响
Extraordinary.
独一无二
Unique.
甚至"美丽"
I would even say 'beautiful'.
先生
Sir,
请放过我吧
please leave me alone.
他们现在不理解 但将来会懂的
They don't understand it, but they will.
这些人真是...
This line is so...
老天呀
Oh, my God! Oh, goodness.
好 安和WD·维勒
OK. Anne and WD Wheeler.
兄妹吗
Brother and sister?
- 是的 - 对
- Yes sir. - Yes.
太好了 你们做什么的
Terrific. And what do you do?
- 空中飞人 - 空中飞人 好
- Trapeze. - Trapeze. OK.
如果你让我们上台 人们会不高兴的
You know, people aren't gonna like it if you put us on the stage.
那最好了
Oh, I am counting on it.
世界第一空中飞人 安和WD
- 这是覆盖了...你的... - 全身
- Is this over your... - Entire body.
好极了 不用给我看了
Terrific. I don't need to see it.
文身男 巴纳姆博物馆
狗孩
我能问问你体重有多少吗
Can I just ask how heavy you are?
有具体的数字吗
Do you have a number for that?
- 我不太想说 但是 - 就你知我知
- I prefer not to say it, but... - Just between you and me.
500磅
500 pounds.
- 你是说750磅吗 - 750磅
- 750 pounds? Is what you said? - 750 pounds!
世界上最胖的人
你叫什么
What's your name?
瓦西里·帕拉沃斯 先生
Vasily Palvos, sir.
你名字得改
Yeah, we are going to change that name.
我觉得你是爱尔兰人
I think you're Irish.
爱尔兰巨人
这表演能成
We have a show.
很好 但要放大五倍
That's good, but I need it five times bigger.
到处都铺满
And I want it everywhere.
马车 火车侧面 电车 板条箱
Carriages, sides of trains, trolleys, crates...
奶瓶 目之所及都能看到
milk bottles, everywhere they look.
巴纳姆美国博物馆
Barnum's American Museum.
见到你很高兴 先生
Nice to see you, sir.
你过得浑浑噩噩
You stumble through your days
脑袋低垂
Got your head hung low
天空也是一片阴霾
Your skies are a shade of grey
连体婴 世界上最高的人
世界上最小的人 伟大的拇指汤姆将军
好像糊里糊涂的僵尸
Like a zombie in a maze
请来两张
Two, please.
你的内心在沉睡
You're asleep inside
但你可以振作清醒
But you can shake awake
因为你犹如行尸走肉
'Cause you're just a dead man walking
还以为那是生活唯一的选择
Think of that your only option
但你可以打开开关 点亮你最晦暗的日子
But you can flip the switch and brighten up your darkest day
高悬的太阳刺得你睁不开眼睛
Sun is up and the color's blinding
重新定义一个崭新的世界
Take a world and redefine it
只要抛开你狭隘的思维
Leave behind your narrow mind
你就能焕然一新
You'll never be the same
清醒过来 活跃起来
Come alive, come alive
点亮你的光芒
Go and light your light
让它发出炫目的光
Let it burn so bright
勇敢向上
Reachin' up
触及天空
To the sky
那里一片开阔
And it's open wide
你也活力四射
You're electrified
世界变成了幻想驰骋的地方
And the world becomes a fantasy
你也超越了自己的一切极限
And you're more than you could ever be
那是因为这是一场白日梦
'Cause you're dreaming with your eyes wide open
你清楚自己无法回到过去
And you know, you can't go back again
回到你曾经生活的世界
To the world that you were living in
因为这是一场盛大的白日梦
'Cause you're dreaming with your eyes wide open
鲜活起来吧
So, come alive
- 莱蒂 他们在等着呢 - 等什么
- Lettie! Lettie! They're waiting! - For what?
- 等你 - 不
- For you. - No.
他们现在还不知道
They don't know it yet,
但他们会爱上你的
but they are gonna love you.
相信我
Trust me.
汤姆
Tom.
上去
Up, up.
你的眼神告诉我
I see it in your eyes
你相信了那个谎言
You believe that lie
说你要藏起自己的真面目
That you need to hide your face
不敢走出家门
Afraid to step outside
于是你把自己锁了起来
So you lock the door
但你绝不能一直如此
But don't you stay that way
再也不用活在阴影中
No more living in those shadows
你和我 清楚那是怎样的生活
You and me, we know how that goes
因为一旦你见识到了 你必将焕发新生
'Cause once you see it, oh you'll never, never be the same
天上打下一道闪电
A little bit of lightnin' strikin'
把它存起来 继续闪耀
Bottled up to keep on shinin'
你可以证明自己还有更多精彩
You can prove there's more to you
不要害怕
You cannot be afraid
清醒过来 活跃起来
Come alive, come alive
点亮你的光芒
Go and light your light
让它发出炫目的光
Let it burn so bright
勇敢向上
Reachin' up
触及天空
To the sky
那里一片开阔
And it's open wide
你也活力四射
You're electrified
世界变成了幻想驰骋的地方
And the world becomes a fantasy
你也超越了自己的一切极限
And you're more than you could ever be
那是因为这是一场白日梦
'Cause you're dreaming with your eyes wide open
你清楚自己无法回到过去
And you know, you can't go back again
回到你曾经生活的世界
To the world that you were living in
因为这是一场盛大的白日梦
'Cause you're dreaming with your eyes wide open
鲜活起来吧
So, come alive
精彩
Bravo.
太棒了
That was great!
- 再来 - 太好了
- More! - Fantastic.
这可不妙
This is bad.
巴纳姆博物馆 粗糙的骗子大杂烩
"罪犯" "贪心"
"Criminal." "Greedy".
"马戏团" 这词我喜欢
"A circus." I like circus.
没错 胖小子
That's right, fat boy!
你要保护那胡子女人吗
You gonna protect the bearded lady?
够了
That's enough.
沃特
Walter.
- 进去 都进去 - 看他们跑了
- Inside, all of you! Right now. - Look them run.
- 我们这里不要你们这种人 - 滚吧
- We don't want your kind here. - Get out of here.
没错 你们这些怪物
That's right, you freaks.
你们的主子叫你们了
Your master's calling.
够了 先生
That's quite enough, sir.
没什么可看的了
Nothing more to look at.
不客气
At your service.
把这则评论登在纽约的每一份报纸上
You print this review in every paper in New York.
带报纸来的人可以享受半价
Half price tickets to anyone who brings it in.
售罄
一个来
Come one!
一起来
Come all!
走进来
Come in!
活起来
Come on!
所有那些梦想迸发的人
To anyone who's bursting with a dream
骗子大王
一个来
Come one!
一起来
Come all!
你听到
You hear!
那召唤
The call!
所有那些寻求解脱的人
To anyone who's searching for a way, to break free
世界变成了幻想驰骋的地方
And the world becomes a fantasy
你也超越了自己的一切极限
And you're more than you could ever be
那是因为这是一场白日梦
'Cause you're dreaming with your eyes wide open
我们清楚自己无法回到过去
And we know, we can't be go back again
回到我们曾经生活的世界
To the world that we were living in
因为这是一场盛大的白日梦
'Cause we're dreaming with our eyes wide open
世界变成了幻想驰骋的地方
And the world becomes a fantasy
你也超越了自己的一切极限
And you're more than you could ever be
那是因为这是一场白日梦
'Cause you're dreaming with your eyes wide open
我们清楚自己无法回到过去
And we know, we can't be go back again
回到我们曾经生活的世界
To the world that we were living in
因为这是一场盛大的白日梦
'Cause we're dreaming with our eyes wide open
鲜活起来吧
So come alive
花生 来买花生啊
Peanuts. Get your peanuts here.
热腾腾的咸花生
Hot, salted peanuts.
我要一份 再给这位女士一份
One for me and one for the lady.
奥马利
O'Malley.
《先驱报》的班内特先生啊
Mr. Bennett from the Herald.
又来看表演了吗
Come to take in another show, huh?
告诉我 巴纳姆先生
Tell me, Mr. Barnum,
你就不介意你卖的东西都是假的吗
does it bother you that everything you're selling is fake?
这些微笑是假的吗
Do these smiles seem fake?
不管是怎么来的 这份欢乐都是真的
It doesn't matter where they come from. The joy is real.
那么你还是慈善家了
So you are a philanthropist?
夸大其词又不是最严重的罪行
Well, hyperbole isn't the worst crime.
想象力匮乏比太丰富更能让人痛苦
Men suffer more from imagining too little than too much.
大骗子的信条啊
The creed of a true fraud.
班内特先生 你上次笑是什么时候了
Mr Bennett, when was the last time you smiled?
或是好好大笑出来
Or had a good laugh? A real laugh.
在剧院里感受不到欢乐的剧评人
A theater critic who can't find joy in the theater.
谁才是骗子啊
Now who is the fraud?
班内特先生
Mr. Bennett.
你用来描述我表演的词
That word you used to describe my show,
叫起来挺上口
has a nice ring to it.
PT·巴纳姆马戏团
这边来
This way.
你不觉得我这辈子盲目信任得够多了吗
Don't you think there is enough 'blind trust' in my life?
这样不才好玩吗
Well, isn't that what makes it fun?
继续走
Keep coming.
好了
Okay.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
- 这是... - 没错
- Is it? - It is.
走吧 我们走
Come on. Let's go.
推
Push.
海伦 那是给你的
Helen, that's for you.
卡罗琳 这是给你的
And, Caroline, this is for you.
街那头就有一家芭蕾舞学校
There is a ballet school right down the street.
在刚过你父母家的地方
Just past your parents' house, actually.
别告诉我你买下这栋房子
Don't tell me you bought this house
就是为了向我父母炫耀你的成功
just to rub my parents' noses in your success.
不是只为了这个
That was not the only reason.
这是我许诺给你的生活
This is the life I promised you.
我们来吧
Shall we?
菲尼
Phin...
这很美 但我们不需要这么奢侈的
It's beautiful, but you know, we don't need all of this to be--
虽然花了我25年的时间
It took me 25 years, but...
欢迎回家 夏瑞蒂·巴纳姆
Welcome home, Charity Barnum.
- 你好 - 巴纳姆来了
- Hello, there. - There goes Barnum.
亲爱的 那个年轻人是谁
Hey, sweetie, who is that young man over there?
那是菲利普·卡莱尔 据说挺风流的
That is Philip Carlyle. A bit of a scandal, they say.
- 他的上部戏剧在伦敦大获成功 - 戏剧
- His last play was a hit in London. - Play?
花大钱
Pay good money to
去看人傻站着念叨两小时
watch people stand around and talk for two hours,
他们还说我是骗子
and they call me a con man.
什么味儿啊 你们闻到了吗
What's that smell? Do you smell that?
是啊 是有股味儿
Ew, something does smell.
我知道了
I know what it is.
是花生
Peanuts.
我现在就能想象得到
I can see it right now.
"市芭蕾舞团史上最年轻的芭蕾舞演员"
"Youngest prima ballerina in the history of the City ballet."
- 我不想跳了 - 什么 为什么不跳了
- I'm quitting. - What? Why would you quit?
我起步太晚 肯定赶不上的
I started too late. I will never catch up.
卡罗琳 你是台上跳得最好的
Caroline, you were the best dancer on that stage.
怎么 你觉得我还分辨不出才艺吗
What? Do you think I can't spot talent?
芭蕾要苦练很多年的
Ballet takes years of hard work.
不像马戏团
It's not like the circus.
不能弄虚作假
You can't just fake it.
她不能放弃 不行 她就是...
She can't quit. No. No, I mean, she just--
她就是觉得跟其他姑娘合不来
She just feels out of place with the other girls.
那最好了
Well, I should certainly hope so.
我这辈子从没见过那么多自命不凡的小公主
I have never seen so many little prima Donnas in my life.
是啊 但那些小公主
Yes, but those prima Donnas
是现在对她最重要的人
are the most important thing in the world to her right now.
她会像我当初一样 学会无视她们的
She'll learn to ignore them, just like I did.
她不该有这个必要
She shouldn't have to.
纽约上流社会永远不会接受我们
New York society will never accept us.
否则 他们还得停止对人评头论足
If they did, they'd have to stop judging
而是真去干点实事
and actually do something with their lives.
这不是为了我
This isn't about me.
那么跟其他的一切不一样咯
So it's different than everything else then?
我就是希望她能以自己的身份 自己的家庭为傲
I just want her to be proud of who she is, of her family.
她是的
She is proud.
我们不非得变成卡莱尔一家
We don't have to be the Carlyle's.
卡莱尔先生 这部剧是你制作的
Mr. Carlyle. You produced this play?
是的
Yes I do, indeed.
前门售票处可退款
Refunds are available at front box office.
- PT·巴纳姆 - 马戏团那个
- P.T. Barnum. - From the circus?
是的 你去过吗
Yes. You've been?
当然没有
God, no.
但我看到了你的顾客
But I've seen the crowds.
看完你表演的人比进门之前要开心多了
People leave your show happier than when they came in.
我的戏剧可就没有同样的效果了
Which is much more than I can say from my play.
但你不愁卖不出票
And yet, you have no trouble selling tickets.
那是因为我卖的是美德
That's because I'm selling virtue.
我能请你喝一杯吗
Can I buy you a drink?
我想争取上流社会的观众
I want to go after the carriage trade.
呈现货真价实的表演 增加我们的卖点
Present legitimate acts, expand our appeal,
争取那些势利眼
go after the snobs.
要是你知道他们多让人受不了
If you only knew how suffocating they are.
那来我们马戏团吧
So come join our circus.
你显然在做娱乐方面颇有天赋
You clearly have a flair for show business.
教我怎么吸引知识分子
Teach me how to appeal to the highbrows.
你说真的吗
Are you serious?
巴纳姆先生 我不能就这么跑去加入马戏团
Mr. Barnum, I can not just run off and join circus.
有何不可 听上去不是挺刺激的
Why not? Sounds thrilling isn't it?
这么说吧 我觉得
Lets just say that I find it
远远欣赏你的表演要更惬意
much more comfortable admiring your show from afar.
惬意 那是进步的敌人
Comfort, the enemy of progress.
你知道吗 光是跟你扯上关系
Do you understand that just associating with you
我就可能失去继承权
could cost me my inheritance.
我觉得应该不止
I thought it'd cost you more than that.
你会赌上一切
You would be risking everything.
但话说回来
But, on the other hand, well,
你或许终于能获得解脱
you just might find yourself a free man.
此地 此时
Right here, right now
我向你发出邀请
I put the offer out
我不想追着求你
I don't want to chase you down
我知道你也心里有数
I know you see it
你跟我干
You run with me
我就能帮你解脱
And I can cut you free
跳出那无聊苦闷的高墙
Out of the drudgery and walls you keep in
抛下一成不变 换来多姿多彩
So trade your typical for somethin' colorful
就算这是发疯 那也不如过把瘾
And if it's crazy, live a little crazy
你可以遵循理智 恪守传统
You can play it sensible, a king of conventional
也可以赌上一把 看看结果如何
Or you can risk it all and see
你难道就不想摆脱桎梏自己的固定角色
Don't you wanna get away from the same old part you gotta play
因为我正有你缺的
'Cause I got what you need
跟我来 过把瘾
So come with me and take the ride
我带你去体验另一种生活
It'll take you to the other side
你可以继续走你的老路
'Cause you can do like you do
也可以试试我的法子
Or you can do like me
可以留在牢笼里 也可以终于拿来钥匙
Stay in the cage, or you'll finally take the key
哎呦喂 这下你便能自由飞翔了
Oh, damn! Suddenly you're free to fly
我带你去体验另一种生活
It'll take you to the other side
行了 朋友 你想拉我入伙
Okay, my friend, you want to cut me in
真是抱歉 但那不可能的
Well I hate to tell you, but it just won't happen
多谢好意 但还是算了
So thanks, but no
我过得好好的
I think I'm good to go
我很喜欢你所谓困住了我的生活
'Cause I quite enjoy the life you say I'm trapped in
我倒是倾佩你 还有你的那套表演
Now I admire you, and that whole show you do
你是有点本事 这我承认
You're onto something, really it's something
但我可是上流人士 我们不用捡花生壳
But I live among the swells, and we don't pick up peanut shells
收拾卫生什么的 还是留给你好了
I'll have to leave that up to you
你难道就不知道我对自己的高贵角色并无不满
Don't you know that I'm okay with this uptown part I get to play
因为我不缺什么
'Cause I got what I need
也不想去过什么瘾
And I don't want to take the ride
我不需要体验另一种生活
I don't need to see the other side
你大可继续你的法子
So go and do like you do
我还是走我的老路
I'm good to do like me
根本不是牢笼 需要什么钥匙
Ain't in a cage, so I don't need to take the key
哎呦喂 没看到我这混得挺好吗
Oh, damn! Can't you see I'm doing fine
我不需要体验另一种生活
I don't need to see the other side
你真就想如此虚度生命吗
Now is this really how you like to spend your days?
借酒消愁 消遣应酬
Whisky, misery and parties and plays?
我要是跟你扯上关系 会被推上风口浪尖
If I were mixed up with you, I'd be the talk of the town
名誉扫地 失去身份 沦为一介小丑
Disgraced and disowned, another one of the clowns
但你会终于能享受生活 开心欢笑
But you would finally live a little, finally laugh a little
只要允许我给你做梦的自由
Just let me give you the freedom to dream and it'll
我就能唤醒你 让你不再痛苦
Wake you up and cure your aching
拆掉你的围墙 让它们崩塌
Take your walls and start 'em breaking
我觉得这笔买卖 你可不亏
Now that's a deal that seems worth taking
但拿主意什么的 还是留给你好了
But I guess I'll leave that up to you
这是有点意思 但答应下来可是代价高昂
Well it's intriguing, but to go would cost me greatly
那么我能拿到表演几成的利润呢
So what percentage of the show would I be taking?
好吧 你当然会想分一杯羹啦
Fair enough, you'd want a piece of all the action
我给你7% 咱们握个手就算成了
I'd give you seven, we could shake and make it happen
我可不是三岁小孩 18%我可以接受
I wasn't born this morning, eighteen would be just fine
你干脆说每挣一毛你要拿一双五分好了
Why not just go ahead and ask for nickels on the dime
15%
Fifteen
我可以给8%
I'd do eight
12%
Twelve
9%勉强可以
Maybe nine
10%
Ten
先生 看来你现在有新合伙人了
Sir, it looks like you have yourself a junior partner.
我是有了个贵得要死的学徒
What I have is an overcompensated apprentice.
你难道就不想换个新角色演演试试
Don't you wanna get away to a whole new part you're gonna play
因为我正有你缺的
'Cause I got what you need,
跟我来 过把瘾
So come with me and take the ride
去体验另一种生活
To the other side
如果你来试试我的法子
So if you do like I do
如果你来走走我的路
So if you do like me
管他什么牢笼 我们自有钥匙
Forget the cage, 'cause we know how to make the key
哎呦喂 这下我们便能自由飞翔了
Oh, damn! Suddenly we're free to fly
我们要去体验另一种生活
We're going to the other side
如果你来试试我的法子
So if you do like I do
体验另一种生活
To the other side
如果你来走走我的路
So if you do like me
我们要去体验另一种生活
We're going to the other side
这样一来 我们就能去体验另一种生活
'Cause if we do we're going to the other side
我们要去体验另一种生活
We're going to the other side
那是谁
Who is that?
这后面可没人买帽子 去前面
No one is buying hats back here. Get out front, go.
WD 安
WD, Anne,
我想向你们介绍我新雇的人
I want to introduce my newest hire,
菲利普·卡莱尔先生
Mr Philip Carlyle.
- 认识你很高兴 - 嗯 幸会
- It's a pleasure to meet you. - Yeah, pleasure.
你是表演什么的 卡莱尔先生
And what is your act, Mr. Carlyle?
我不做表演
I don't have an act.
每个人都有自己的表演
Everyone has got an act.
- 巴纳姆先生 - 怎么
- Mr. Barnum. - Yeah?
你最好来看看
You better come see this.
菲利普 跟上
Philip, keep up.
- 不和谐的元素 - 一向都有 是吧
- A bit of nasty element. - There always is, isn't there?
看客最能吸引看客了
Nothing draws a crowd crying like a crowd.
滚回去 怪物
Go home you freaks.
怪物
Freak!
城市污点
"Shame of the city".
巴纳姆马戏团引发抗议
抗议坐实了巴纳姆先生
"The protests cement Mr. Barnum's reputation
粗鄙和下流的提供者的名声
"as a purveyor of the offensive and indecent."
"粗鄙下流"
"Offensive and indecent."
班内特先生 我都不好意思了
Mr. Bennett, I'm blushing.
不 我才不好意思
No, I'm blushing.
你管班内特怎么想呢
What do you care what Bennett thinks?
- 他是个混蛋 - 还是个势利眼
- He's a prick. - And a snob.
是啊 但全纽约的势利眼都看他的文章
Yeah, all the snobs in the New York are reading him.
他告诉他们该怎么想
He does their thinking for them.
不是说要靠争议制造热度吗
What ever happened to the thriving of controversy?
是啊 但是
Yeah, well... Look, hey..
- 你对此有什么想法吗 - 菲利普
- Do you have any thoughts on this? - Philip.
- 事实上 我还真有 - 海伦 过来
- You know what, as a matter of fact, I do. - Helen, come on.
王室总管
"The master of the Household,
应女王陛下的要求
has it in the command of the Queen...
邀请菲尼斯·T·巴纳姆先生和他的剧团
To invite Mr. Phineas T Barnum and his theatrical troop
去白金汉宫赴宴
to a reception at Buckingham Palace."
维多利亚女王 真的假的
The Queen Victoria? Is this real?
我动用了些关系
I had to pull a few strings.
如果你想要上流社会接纳你
If you want society to accept you,
那就不如从最上层开始
you may as well start at the very very top.
我们都受邀了吗
Are we all invited?
那我只能告诉女王 我们要么一起去
I guess I'll just have to tell the queen either all of us go
要么就都不去
or none of us will.
英国女王 可没有比这更厉害的了
The Queen of England. Can't get much better than that.
- 我们怎么不穿燕尾服 - 我们是来做表演的
- Why aren't we in tails? - We are the entertainment.
你可没穿戏服
I don't see you in a costume.
女王陛下 菲尼斯·T·巴纳姆先生和他的
Your Majesty, Mr Phineas T Barnum and his...
美国奇人
Oddities from America.
那是真的吗
Is that real?
女王陛下
Your Majesty,
容我介绍
may I present
巴纳姆先生
Mr Barnum.
我很荣幸 巴纳姆先生
The honor is mine, Mr. Barnum.
我从我美国的朋友那里听说了
And I've heard all about your little colonel
你的小上校
from my friends in America.
是将军 女士
General, ma'am.
你比我想的还要小
You are even smaller than I imagined.
你自己也
Well, you are not exactly
不算是很高啊 亲爱的
reaching the top self yourself sweetheart.
挺顺利嘛
Ah, that went well.
- 女王陛下 - 菲利普
- Your Majesty. - Philip.
珍妮·林德小姐
Miss Jenny Lind.
她真是光彩照人
She is really luminous.
- 那是谁 - 歌剧歌手
- Who is that? - The opera singer.
歌手啊
Singer, huh?
她是全欧洲最著名的歌手
She is the most famous performer in all of Europe.
她在斯卡拉十几场演出都售罄
She has sold out La Scala a dozen times.
还有法国剧院
Not to mention the French Opera.
- 你干什么 - 跟着你
- What are you doing? - Following you...
等你把我介绍给林德小姐
so you can introduce me to Miss Lind.
- 介绍你 - 对
- Introduce you? - Yeah.
我都不认识她
I don't know her.
人人都认识她 你自己刚说的
Everybody knows her. You just said so yourself.
是啊 你不能就这么冲到这样的人面前
Yeah, exactly. You don't just march up to someone like this.
有何不可 我们相貌堂堂 她也是个人嘛
Why not? We're personable. She's a person.
林德小姐
Miss Lind.
我是菲利普·卡莱尔
My name is Phillip Carlyle.
我身边这位了不起的先生
And this extraordinary gentleman next to me...
菲尼斯·泰勒·巴纳姆 很荣幸
Phineas Taylor Barnum. The pleasure is mine.
当然 你是那个美国人
Of course, you are the American.
我好像是听说过你
I believe I might have heard of you.
是嘛 如果你在大洋彼岸都听说过我
Oh well, if you've heard of me all the way over here,
我肯定是美名远扬
I must be doing something right.
或是臭名昭著
That, or something very wrong.
就宣传而言 这没什么区别
In the world of publicity there is hardly any difference.
死皮赖脸的人才这么说呢 巴纳姆先生
I believe those are the words of a scoundrel, Mr Barnum.
是马戏团老板 林德小姐 仅此而已
A showman, Miss Lind, just a showman.
而且是大西洋我们这边最好的一位
The best on my side of the Atlantic.
既然你都这么说了
If you do say so yourself.
我是说了 但我不用说的
I do, but I don't have to.
是啊 他是最好的之一
Oh, no, no. He is one of the best.
太客气了 林德小姐 我直说吧
That's very kind of you. Miss Lind, let me get to the point.
我想请你去纽约 如果你愿意
I would like to bring you to New York. And if you agree
我还会让你成为
I'll make you the most famous singer
不仅是欧洲 而是全世界最著名的歌手
not in Europe but in the entire world.
你听过我唱歌吗
And have you heard me sing?
- 当然 - 没有
- Absolutely. - No, I haven't.
但你像我一样 早已声名远播
But like mine, your reputation precedes you
而比起我的品位 我更相信你的名声
and well, I trust your reputation more than my own taste, so...
我还没去过美国呢
I have never been to America.
你将在世界上最伟大的城市
You will sing in the grandest theater...
最豪华的剧院 最好的乐队伴奏下演唱
with the finest orchestra in the greatest city on earth.
珍妮·林德 仅此一晚
"Jenny Lind". "One night only."
或许两晚
Or maybe two.
再加20%的票房 你将收入不菲
And add 20% of the gate, it will be a queen's ransom for your efforts.
我大部分收入都捐给了慈善事业 巴纳姆先生
I gave most of my earnings to charity, Mr Barnum,
捐给孤儿寡妇
to orphans and widows.
"夜莺嗓音 天使之心"
"Voice of a nightingale, Heart of an Angel."
太棒了 媒体会疯狂报道这样的故事
That's brilliant. I mean the press will go crazy with that story.
这可不是什么故事
That's not a story.
我能问你件事吗 巴纳姆先生
May I ask you something, Mr. Barnum?
请讲
Anything.
为什么要我
Why me?
人们来看我的表演是为了开心地被骗
People come to my show for the pleasure of being hoodwinked.
就这一次 我想给他们点真实的东西
Just once, I would love to give them something real.
里德小姐
Miss Lind.
珍妮·林德
所有人都来了 看啊
Everyone is here. Look at this.
温斯洛普夫妇都来了
Even the Winthrops.
你开心了吗
Are you happy?
如果成功 我就开心了
I will be, if this works.
天呐 希望她唱得好
Oh, God, I hope she can sing.
- 她怎么还没出来 - 他们还在就坐
- What's taking her so long? - They are still taking their seats.
说到这个
Speaking of which.
- 汤姆和莱蒂他们刚到了 - 什么
- Tom and Lettie, the others, they just arrived. - What?
我该叫他们坐哪 你的包厢吗
Where should I put them? Your box?
- 包厢 不行 太显眼了 - 显眼
- That box? No, no, no, that's a bit visible. - Visible?
两侧的站席音效其实更好
The acoustics are actually better in the standing room.
让他们去那里吧
That's where they should be.
林德小姐准备好了
Miss Lind is ready now.
好 谢谢 太好了
OK. Thank you. Thank God.
这里好棒
This is so awesome.
- 多美啊 - 是啊
- Isn't it wonderful? - Yeah.
我好喜欢
I love it.
女士们先生们 感谢大家耐心等待
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your patience.
他上不了这种台面
He's out of his element.
这怎么回事
What is this about?
那是巴纳姆吗
Is that Barnum?
这里又不是马戏团
This isn't the circus.
我最近有幸
I recently had the privilege of
听到了世界上
hearing the most divine voice
最动人的歌声
I've ever heard.
他还突然成鉴赏家了
Suddenly he's a connoisseur.
我知道这听上去像是巴纳姆的吹嘘
Now, I know that sounds like Barnum humbug...
但我冰镇了一百瓶上好的香槟 我敢保证
but I have a 100 bottles of good champagne on ice that says
这可不是什么新奇的小表演
this isn't just another sideshow novelty.
有请 瑞典夜莺
May I present, the Swedish Nightingale...
珍妮·林德小姐
Miss Jenny Lind.
我努力想屏住呼吸
I'm tryin' to hold my breath
让时间凝固
Let it stay this way
不愿让这一刻结束
Can't let this moment end
你在我心中埋下一个梦想
You set off a dream in me
它越来越响亮
Gettin' louder now
你能否听到那回音
Can you hear it echoing?
握住我的手
Take my hand
你可愿与我分享此刻
Will you share this with me?
亲爱的 如果没有你
'Cause darling without you
哪怕是千万盏聚光灯的光芒
All the shine of a thousand spotlights
哪怕是我们从夜空中偷来的全部星光
All the stars we steal from the night sky
也永远无法让我满足
Will never be enough
无法让我满足
Never be enough
黄金高塔也还是不够大
Towers of gold are still too little
我能把世界握在手中 可那也
These hands could hold the world but it'll
无法让我满足
Never be enough
无法满足
For me
永远 永远
Never, never
永远 无法
Never, for me
满足
For me
无法让我满足
Never enough
无法满足
For me
哪怕是千万盏聚光灯的光芒
All the shine of a thousand spotlights
哪怕是我们从夜空中偷来的全部星光
All the stars we steal from the night sky
也永远无法让我满足
Will never be enough
无法让我满足
Never be enough
黄金高塔也还是不够大
Towers of gold are still too little
我能把世界握在手中 可那也
These hands could hold the world but it'll
无法让我满足
Never be enough
无法满足
For me
永远 永远
Never, never
永远 无法
Never, for me
满足
For me
无法让我满足
Never enough
永远 永远
Never, never
无法让我满足
Never enough
永远 永远
Never, never
无法让我满足
Never enough
无法满足
For me
太精彩了
Brava!
- 太棒了 - 再来一首
- Brava! - More!
太美了
Wonderful!
精彩
Bravissima!
再来
More!
太棒了
Brava!
安可
Encore.
珍妮 这是我妻子夏瑞蒂和我们的女儿
Jenny, this is my wife Charity and our girls.
当然 我听说了你们好多事呢
Of course, and I've heard so much about you.
你父亲还告诉我你喜欢芭蕾舞
And your father tells me you are a fan of the ballet.
- 是的 我在学芭蕾 - 是吗
- Yes, I'm studying ballet. - Oh, are you?
- 当然了 - 当然了
- Of course I am. - Of course she is.
- 那你呢 海伦 - 你像个公主 女士
- And what about you, Helen? - You look like a princess, ma'am.
我得承认 巴纳姆 她的确非同一般
I have to admit, Barnum, she is remarkable.
就连最无趣的评论家也觉得有趣了 是吗
Enough to bring joy to the most joyless critic, isn't she?
如果是由真正的艺术经理人打理
And in the hands of a real purveyor of the arts,
她真的可以在这个国家大有发展
she could be something in this country.
可惜她搭上了你
Shame she's fallen in with you.
你真是在纸面上更讨喜 班内特先生
You really are better on the page, Mr Bannet.
虽然这难以置信
Hard is that is to believe.
巴纳姆先生 我想见见林德小姐
Mr. Barnum? I would love to meet Miss Lind.
当然可以 请稍等一下
And you will meet miss Lind if you just give me a moment...
- 菲尼斯 - 嗯
- Phineas. - Yes.
你做得不错
You've done well.
谢谢
Thank you.
容我为你们引见
Allow me to introduce you.
打扰下 珍妮 见见夏瑞蒂的父母
Excuse me, Jenny. I would like you to meet Charity's parents.
- 哈利特先生和太太 - 幸会
- Mr and Mrs Hallett. - Ah, pleasure.
- 你好 认识你很高兴 - 认识你很高兴
- How do you do? Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
- 妈妈 - 你好 亲爱的
- Mother. - Hello dear.
- 这是 - 是啊 那是你的外孙女
- Are these... - Yes, yes, those are your granddaughters.
- 菲尼斯 别在这儿闹 - 是吗
- Phineas, not here. - Not here?
你担心我会在你父母的体面朋友面前
You are afraid that I'm gonna embarrass your parents
让他们下不来台吗
in front of their fancy friends?
我恐怕是没那个本事
I really don't think that I have that power.
就我这样的小人物
An insignificant man like me...
显然注定只能过渺小的一生
who was clearly destined to lead an insignificant life.
就算腰缠万贯 也还是那个裁缝的儿子
All that fortune and still just a tailor's boy.
滚出去
Get out.
好吧 菲尼斯
Well, Phineas...
我不是跟你说过 免费香槟
I believe that I told you that free champagne
肯定要搞出麻烦来
is a recipe for disaster.
夏瑞蒂
Charity.
- 请大家举杯 - 夏瑞蒂
- Now would everyone please raise their glasses? - Charity.
敬巴纳姆先生 他永远地证明了
To Mr Barnum, who showed once and for all
一个人的地位只受他眼界的限制
that a man's station is limited only by his imagination.
- 敬巴纳姆 - 谢谢
- To Barnum. - Thank you.
敬巴纳姆先生
To Mr Barnum.
谢谢
Thank you.
生来拥有财富和特权的人
It's hard to understand wealth and privileges
反而不懂它的重要性
when you're born into it.
我有时也觉得自己不属于这里
I sometimes don't feel like I belong here.
你怎么会
You?
我是个私生女
I was born out of wedlock
这给我的家族蒙了羞
and that brought shame upon my family.
生活总能提醒我
And life always manages to remind me
我不配在这世上存在
that I don't deserve a place in this world.
这留下了起立鼓掌永远无法填补的空虚
And that leaves a hole that no ovation can ever fill.
- 菲尼斯先生 - 大伙儿们
- Mr. Phineas! - Guys...
- 天呐 那女士真能唱 - 是啊
- Lord, that lady can sing. - I know.
你觉得她会喜欢穿制服的男人吗
Thinks she likes a man in uniform?
她肯定喜欢
I'm sure she does.
你们干什么呢 你们一小时后还要上台呢
What are you doing here? You got a show in an hour, OK?
那我们至少也有时间喝三杯了
That's enough time for us to have at least three drinks, right?
来吧
Come on.
- 不行 莱蒂 - 怎么了
- No no. Lettie. - What?
这里已经很挤了 你们不能进去交际
It's very crowded in here, okay? And I can't have you mingling.
各位 如果你们就这么抛头露面
Guys, who's gonna pay admission
谁还会花钱买门票啊
if you are out there for all the world to see.
- 表演顺利 - 等等
- Have a great show. - Wait...
女士们先生们 请举杯
Ladies and gentlemen, a toast.
珍妮 美国现在还不知道
Jenny, America may not know it yet,
但他们会爱上你的
but they are going to love you.
敬林德小姐
To Miss Lind.
我对黑暗并不陌生
I'm not a stranger to the dark
人们都说 躲起来吧
Hide away, they say
我们并不想看到你残破的样子
'Cause we don't want your broken parts
我的缺陷都成了羞耻的标记
I've learned to be ashamed of all my scars
人们都说 快跑掉吧
Run away, they say
没人会喜欢你真实的模样
No one will love you as you are
但我不会允许他们把我碾压成尘
But I won't let them break me down to dust
我知道这世界有我们容身的地方
I know that there's a place for us
因为我们是如此绚丽
For we are glorious
当尖刻的话语像刀枪要将我击垮
When the sharpest words wanna cut me down
通往大街
我要释放滚滚洪流淹没他们的叫嚣
I'm gonna send a flood, gonna drown them out
我勇敢 我有伤
I am brave, I am bruised
我是本就灿烂的我 我就是这样
I am who I'm meant to be, this is me
小心点 我要来了
Look out 'cause here I come
我和着自己敲响的鼓点大步向前
And I'm marching on to the beat I drum
我不怕被人看到
I'm not scared to be seen
也不为自己道歉 我就是这样
I make no apologies, this is me
他们怎么跑到这儿来了
What are they doing here?
又一轮讥讽的子弹打在我身上
Another round of bullets hits my skin
你们开火吧 今天 我不会再被羞耻压垮
Well, fire away 'cause today, I won't let the shame sink in
我们要冲破重重阻碍
We are bursting through the barricades
往太阳的方向前进
And reaching for the sun
我们是勇士
We are warriors
没错 这就是如今的我们
Yeah, that's what we've become
我不会允许他们把我碾压成尘
I won't let them break me down to dust
我知道这世界有我们容身的地方
I know that there's a place for us
滚回家
Go home.
因为我们是如此绚丽
For we are glorious
当尖刻的话语像刀枪要将我击垮
When the sharpest words wanna cut me down
我要释放滚滚洪流淹没他们的叫嚣
I'm gonna send a flood, gonna drown them out
我勇敢 我有伤
I am brave, I am bruised
我是本就灿烂的我 我就是这样
I am who I'm meant to be, this is me
小心点 我要来了
Look out 'cause here I come
我和着自己敲响的鼓点大步向前
And I'm marching on to the beat I drum
我不怕被人看到
I'm not scared to be seen
也不为自己道歉 我就是这样
I make no apologies, this is me
我就是这样
...This is me
我清楚我值得被爱
And I know that I deserve your love
我没什么配不上的
There's nothing I'm not worthy of
当尖刻的话语像刀枪要将我击垮
When the sharpest words wanna cut me down
我要释放滚滚洪流淹没他们的叫嚣
I'm gonna send a flood, gonna drown them out
这是勇敢 是受过伤
This is brave, this is bruised
这是注定灿烂的我 我就是这样
This is who I'm meant to be, this is me
小心点 我要来了
Look out 'cause here I come (look out 'cause here I come)
我和着自己敲响的鼓点大步向前
And I'm marching on to the beat I drum
- 大步向前 - 和着自己敲响的鼓点
- Marchin' on, marchin', marchin' on - To the beat I drum
我不怕被人看到
I'm not scared to be seen
也不为自己道歉 我就是这样
I make no apologies, this is me
当尖刻的话语像刀枪要将我击垮
Whenever the words wanna cut me down
我要释放滚滚洪流淹没他们的叫嚣
I'll send the flood to drown 'em out
我要释放滚滚洪流
I'm gonna send a flood
淹没他们的叫嚣
Gonna drown them out
我就是这样
This is me
珍妮·林德
怎么就不能在纽约多办几场表演
Why can't you just put more shows in New York?
何必非要全国巡演
Why do you need to tour the country?
拿破仑为什么要进攻俄国
Why did Napoleon march on Russia?
拿破仑被打败了啊
Napoleon was defeated.
拿破仑没有60人管弦乐队
Napoleon didn't have a 60 piece orchestra.
60人管弦乐队
A 60 piece orchestra.
请最便宜的乐师 这个交给你
Just get the cheapest musicians you can, you watch that.
我们还得包食宿
We still have to aboard them.
请夫妻 让他们睡一个铺
Well, get married ones. They can share a bunk.
奥马利 那是卡罗琳的储蓄罐
O'Malley, that's Caroline's piggy bank.
- 定制布景 - 嗯
- Costumes sets? - Yeah.
焰火 在剧院内放吗
Fireworks? Inside theaters?
好点子
That's genius.
不 PT 这都是国内最负盛名的剧院
No. P.T. these are the most famous theaters in the country.
他们会要你提前包下门票
They make you buy the seats in advance
- 才能订场地 - 是啊 我贷了款
- just to book them. - Yeah, yeah. I took out a loan.
我们还要给珍妮报酬
And we have to pay Jenny
- 而且是预付 - 贷了挺大一笔
- in advance? - It was a large loan. Okay?
你在第40场表演之前都无法盈利
You're not gonna see a penny of profit until your 40th show.
其实是41场
41st actually.
你赌上了你建立的一切
You're risking everything you've built here.
你以为这一切怎么建起来的
How do you think I build it?
这之后就能有足够利润了
We'll have plenty of profits to go around after this.
- PT - 怎么了
- P.T? - What?
你的注意力已经被分散太久了
Your attention has been divided long enough.
我们上座率下降了 每天都有更多人来抗议
Our gate is down, we have more protesters every day.
你需要拢住回头客
You just need to get people to come back.
如果你最近没去过巴纳姆博物馆
"If you haven't been to Barnum museum lately,
就肯定不知道里面什么样
You have not been to the Barnum Museum."
他们是来看你的
They come to see you.
你的疯狂点子 你的新表演 不寻常的景象
Your crazy ideas, your new acts, the unusual.
那你给他们笑一个好了 那多不寻常
Then how about you show them your smile. That would be unusual.
继续彩排 让他们清楚我要求他们
Keep rehearsing. Just make it very clear that I expect them
对你表现出应有的尊重
to afford you all the deference you deserve...
而且他们本来也该对你客客气气的
And that they should be nice to you anyway.
真让人看了就开心啊
Ain't that a sight for sore eyes?
- 都不说声你好 - 或是再见
- He couldn't even say hello. - Or goodbye.
他要去巡演了 抱歉 各位
He is going on tour. Sorry guys.
别垂头丧气的 卡莱尔 你不是还要赴约吗
Pull yourself together, Carlyle. Don't you have somewhere to be?
安·维勒
Anne Wheeler.
巴纳姆先生说他给我留了票
Mr. Barnum said he left a ticket for me.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
应该是只有一张的
I believe there's only supposed to be one.
不 就是两张
No, there's meant to be two.
我怕我直接约你不会答应
Wasn't sure you'd come if I asked.
五分钟后开场
Five minutes to curtains.
我一直想进剧院
I've always wanted to go to the theater.
菲利普 是你吗
Phillip, is that you?
妈妈 爸爸
Mother. Father.
这位是安·维勒
This is Anne Wheeler.
菲利普 你不知耻吗
Phillip, have you no shame?
跟巴纳姆的生意扯上关系还是一码事
To associate yourself with that Barnum business is one thing...
居然还带着女佣出来招摇过市
but parading around with the help.
安
Anne.
你怎么敢那么对她说话
How dare you speak to her like that?
- 你忘记自己的身份了 菲利普 - 我的身份
- You forget your place, Phillip. - My place?
妈妈 如果我的身份就这样
Mother, if this is my place,
那我一点也不想要
then I don't want any part of it.
安
Anne.
他们是狭隘的人
They are small minded people.
- 你何必在意他们说什么 - 不止是他们
- Why do you care what they think? - It's not just them.
你从没感受过
You've never had somebody look at you
你父母投给我的那种眼光
the way your parents looked at me.
所有人都会对我们投来那样的眼光
The way everyone would look at us.
你知道我渴望你
You know I want you
这并非秘密 我不想隐瞒
It's not a secret I try to hide
我知道你渴望我
I know you want me
别说什么我们无能为力
So don't keep saying our hands are tied
你说你没有这命
You claim it's not in the cards
命运将你拉到天涯海角
But fate is pulling you miles away
让我无法触及
And out of reach from me
可你就在我心中
But you're here in my heart
那么谁又能阻止我认定
So who can stop me if I decide
你就是我的命中注定
That you're my destiny?
或许我们可以改写星运
What if we rewrite the stars?
让你成为我的注定
Say you were made to be mine
没什么能让我们分离
Nothing could keep us apart
而你是我最终的归宿
You'd be the one I was meant to find
这由你决定
It's up to you
也由我决定
And it's up to me
没人能决定我们非要如何
No one can say what we get to be
那我们何不改写星运
So why don't we rewrite the stars?
或许世界也可以由我们掌握
Maybe the world could be ours
哪怕只此一夜
Tonight
你以为这不让我痛苦
You think it's easy
你以为我不想冲到你身边吗
You think I don't want to run to you
但我们之间的阻隔犹如大山
But there are mountains
或是无论如何都跨不过的门槛
And there are doors that we can't walk through
我知道你并不信服
I know you're wondering why
因为我们可以
Because we're able to be
只做自己
Just you and me
但那是在这个小世界里
Within these walls
一旦我们出去
But when we go outside
你便会清醒地认识到 这根本毫无希望
You're gonna wake up and see that it was hopeless after all
没人能改写星运
No one can rewrite the stars
你怎么能说你会属于我
How can you say you'll be mine
一切都在分离我们
Everything keeps us apart
我也并非你最终的归宿
And I'm not the one you were meant to find
你决定不了
It's not up to you
我决定不了
It's not up to me
每个人都认定了我们应当如何
When everyone tells us what we can be
我们怎么能改写星运
How can we rewrite the stars?
傻傻认为世界可以由我们掌握
Say that the world can be ours
哪怕只此一夜
Tonight
我只想与你一起翱翔
All I want is to fly with you
我只想与你一起坠落
All I want is to fall with you
所以把你的一切交给我
So just give me all of you
这似乎全无可能
It feels impossible
这并非全无可能
It's not impossible
这是否全无可能
Is it impossible?
告诉我这仍有可能
Say that it's possible
我们要如何改写星运
How do we rewrite the stars?
让你成为我的注定
Say you were made to be mine?
没什么能让我们分离
Nothing can keep us apart
因为你是我最终的归宿
Cause you are the one I was meant to find
这由你决定
It's up to you
也由我决定
And it's up to me
没人能决定我们非要如何
No one can say what we get to be
我们何不改写星运
Why don't we rewrite the stars?
改变世界让它由我们掌握
Changing the world to be ours
你知道我渴望你
You know I want you
这并非秘密 我不想隐瞒
It's not a secret I try to hide
但我不能拥有你
But I can't have you
我们注定要分离
We're bound to break and
我也无能为力
My hands are tied
先是在我父母家旁边买了房子
First it was buying a house on the same street as my parents.
然后又是去见女王
Then meeting the queen.
然后请来了珍妮·林德
Then bringing Jenny Lind,
那晚又跟我父亲针锋相对
then my father the other night.
你什么时候才算满足啊
When will it ever be enough for you?
我这么做是为了卡罗琳和海伦
I am doing this for Caroline and Helen.
抬眼看看啊 她们什么都不缺了
Look around you. They have everything.
- 你不懂 - 我懂
- You don't understand. - I do.
不 你不懂
No. You don't understand!
你怎么能懂呢
How could you?
我父亲被视如粪土
My father was treated like dirt.
我也曾被视如粪土
I was treated like dirt.
我的孩子绝不能再如此
My children will not be.
你不需要让每个人都爱你 菲尼
You don't need everyone to love you, Phin.
就几个好人就够了
Just a few good people.
我知道
I know that.
- 谢谢 - 先生
- Thank you. - Sir.
不 爸爸
No. Daddy.
爸爸
Daddy.
爸爸 别走 等等
Daddy, no. Wait.
- 爸爸 - 走吧
- Daddy. - Go.
等等 爸爸
Wait, Daddy.
有的人渴望简单的生活 规划明确
Some people long for a life that is simple and planned
像精致的束缚
Tied with a ribbon
有的人不肯去海上出航 因为陆上更安稳
Some people won't sail the sea 'cause they're safer on land
只遵从既定轨迹
To follow what's written
但我追随你 步入无限未知
But I'd follow you to the great unknown
前往属于我们自己的世界
Off to a world we call our own
山岳峡谷星星点点 点缀在
Mountains and valleys, and all that will come in between
沙漠和大海之间
Desert and ocean
你拉上我 我们一起沉溺于梦中
You pulled me in and together we're lost in a dream
时刻变幻
Always in motion
我赌上一切 只为与你同行
So I risk it all just to be with you
我赌上一切 选择了我们的生活
And I risk it all for this life we choose
手握着手
Hand in my hand
你说好永远不放手
And you promised to never let go
我们在走着钢丝
We're walking the tightrope
云霄之上
High in the sky
我们把脚下世界尽收眼底
We can see the whole world down below
我们在走着钢丝
We're walking the tightrope
无从知道 一旦坠落 你可会接住我
Never sure Will you catch me if I should fall
但这是一场冒险
But it's all an adventure
而且一路上风景美不胜收
That comes with a breathtaking view
走着钢丝
Walking the tightrope
与你一起
With you...
辛辛那提酒店
就好像我们终于第一次知道
"It is as though we've learned for the first time...
珍妮·林德巡演大获成功
歌唱的真正意义
what singing really is."
林德小姐理当得到我国最高的尊敬
Miss Lind deserves our nation's highest esteem
和最热情的掌声
and lavish ovations.
- 天呐 - 世界拜倒在我们脚下了
- I mean... - The world at our feet.
好了 巴纳姆先生
Well, Mr. Barnum.
这杯酒
This...
敬
is...
实现梦想
to making dreams come true.
谢谢 珍妮
Thank you, Jenny.
还有两小时开场
It's two hours to curtains.
我已经给了你全世界 是吧
I've given you the world, haven't I?
我该走了
I, I should go.
我让你分心了 对不起 珍妮
I have become a distraction. I'm sorry, Jenny.
- 不 - 你自己完成巡演吧
- No. - You should finish your tour without me.
什么 你要走了
What? You're leaving?
- 行程都规划好了 - 就这样了
- The itinerary is well in hand. - So that's it.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我只不过又是你的一个节目
I'm just another your acts.
- 珍妮 - 我不干了
- Jenny. - I'm done.
珍妮 拜托
Jenny, Jenny, please.
你必须完成巡演
You have to finish the tour.
- 是吗 - 否则我就完了
- Must I? - It will ruin me.
如果你待人不谨慎 巴纳姆先生
When you're careless with other people, Mr Barnum,
就是自毁前程
you bring ruin upon yourself.
- 我赌上了一切 - 我也是
- I have risked everything. - Well, so did I.
看来我们都输了
It seems we've both lost.
哪怕是我们从夜空中偷来的全部星光
All the stars we steal from the night sky
也永远无法让我满足
Will never be enough
无法让我满足
Never be enough
黄金高塔也还是不够大
Towers of gold are still too little
我能把世界握在手中 可那也
These hands could hold the world but it'll
无法让我满足
Never be enough
谢谢
Thank you.
这是干什么
What was that?
告别
That was goodbye.
谢谢各位前来
Thank you very much for coming.
- 去告诉朋友街邻 - 表演真精彩
- Tell your friends and neighbors. - What a wonderful show.
谁看得开心 你吗
Who enjoyed yourselves? You? You?
告诉别人你们在马戏团看得多开心
Tell everyone how much fun you had at the circus.
每晚都有新节目
New acts every night.
马戏团长
Hey, ringmaster.
先生们 我得请你们离开了
Gentlemen, I am gonna have to ask you to leave.
这是我们的城市 小子
This is our town, son.
你们才该走 你和你的怪物
We think you should leave, you and your freaks.
你的黑鬼
And yours spooks.
先生
Sir.
我只再说一遍
I will only ask once more.
然后怎样 小子
Then what, boy?
住手
Stop!
打他
Get him!
冲啊
Charge.
爸爸
Daddy.
姑娘们
Girls. Girls. Girls.
你们长得好快 不许再长了
You are growing so much. Stop it!
你怎么决定提前回来了
What made you decide to come back early?
我想你了
I missed you.
- 我想你了 - 这听上去好像是唬人的话呢
- I missed you. - That sounds an awful lot like Humbug.
着火了
Fire.
让路 着火了
Out of the way. Fire!
快 是马戏团那边着起来的
Hurry, it's coming from the circus.
姑娘们 跟上我 跟上 快来
Girls, stay with me, stay with me. Come. Quick, quick!
大家都跟紧了
Everyone! Stay close.
菲利普 大家都出来了吗
Phillip, is everyone out?
- 大家都没事吧 - 嗯
- Is everyone okay? - Yeah.
动物呢
The animals? The animals?
放了 还能怎么办
We set them free. What else could we do?
- WD 安呢 - 安在哪
- WD, where is Anne? - Where is Anne?
别 菲利普 别去
No, Phillip. No.
不 站住 你不能进去
No. Stop. You can not go inside.
安
Anne.
菲利普
Philip!
继续泵水
Keep pumping.
- WD - 她出来了
- WD. - There she is. There she is.
菲利普
Phillip.
- 菲利普 - 爸爸
- Phillip. - Daddy.
- 不要 爸爸 - 爸爸
- No, Daddy! - Daddy!
不要
No.
别过去
Stay back, please.
爸爸
Daddy.
担架
Stretcher, stretcher.
他吸了很多烟 他还有气 快
He's taken a lot of smoke. He's still breathing. Come on.
把他抬上去
Come on, let's get him on!
起
Up.
或许我们可以改写星运
What if we rewrite the stars?
让你成为我的注定
Say you were meant to be mine?
没什么能让我们分离
Nothing can keep us apart
而你是我最终的归宿
you are the one I was meant to find.
走吧
Here we go, guys!
往前走
Come on, straight ahead.
如果你是来幸灾乐祸的 还是算了
If you had come to gloat I wouldn't.
纵火的暴徒被抓到了
They caught the thugs who started the fire.
我觉得你会想知道
I thought you'd like to know.
我从不喜欢你的表演
I never liked your show.
但我一直觉得观众很喜欢
But I always thought the people did.
是啊 他们一直喜欢
They did. They do.
不过 我可不会称之为艺术
Mind you, I wouldn't call it art.
当然了
Of course not.
但是
But...
让各种各样的人跟你一起站在舞台上
Putting folks of all kinds on stage with you.
不论他们有何肤色 体型
All colors, shapes, sizes.
都将他们平等地呈现出来
Presenting them as equals.
换了别的评论家甚至可能称之为
Another critic might have even called it
"人性的颂歌"
'a celebration of humanity'.
我喜欢这个
I would have liked that.
希望你会重建
Well, I hope you'll rebuild.
幸好还有珍妮的巡演 可以从利润里拿出钱来
Thank god for Jenny's tour. We can borrow off the profits.
我们没事的
We'll be fine.
你不知道吗
You don't know?
珍妮·林德退出巡演
真遗憾
I'm sorry.
巴纳姆丑闻
夏瑞蒂
Charity?
天呐 夏瑞蒂
Oh God, Charity.
- 我... - 我不想跟你说话
- I am... - I don't wanna talk to you.
- 根本什么都没发生 - 什么都没发生
- Nothing happened. - Oh, sure, nothing happened.
纽约所有的报纸都登了
It's on the cover of every paper in New York.
是她设计了那张照片 我并不爱她
Because she orchestrated the photo. I am not in love with her.
当然了
Of course you're not.
不爱她 不爱我 不爱任何人
Not with her, not with me, not with anyone.
只爱你和你的表演
Just you and your show.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我要回家
I'm going home.
这就是你的家
This is your home.
银行
The bank..
要驱逐我们了
They are evicting us.
你怎么贷款前不问过我
Why didn't you ask me before?
我本也会同意的
I would have said yes.
我从不介意要冒险 但我们一向是共进退
I never minded the risk, but we always did it together.
就猜到你会跑来这里 自怨自艾
Figured you'd end up here. Feeling sorry for yourself?
各位 如果你们是来拿工资的
Folks if you have come to get paid,
没钱了 一个子都没了
the money's gone. All of it.
- 没剩什么可... - 闭嘴吧 巴纳姆
- Nothing left to give... - Shut up, Barnum.
你还不懂吗
You just don't get it.
我们的亲生母亲都嫌我们丢人
Our own mothers were ashamed of us.
一直把我们藏着掖着
Hid us our whole lives.
然后你把我们从阴影里拽出来
Then you pull us out of the shadows.
现在你也要放弃我们了
And now you are giving upon us too.
或许你真是个骗子
Maybe you are fraud.
或许真的只是为了赚钱
Maybe it was just about making a buck.
但你给了我们一个真正的家庭
But you gave us a real family.
马戏团
And the circus
就是我们的家园
that was our home.
我们想要回我们的家
We want our home back.
看那日薄西山
I saw the sun begin to dim
感到冬风渐起
And felt that winter wind
吹人冷
Blow cold
患难才能见真情
A man learns who is there for him
当浮华褪去 高墙崩塌
When the glitter fades and the walls won't hold
废墟瓦砾之中
'Cause from that rubble
依然矗立
What remains
必是至真至诚
Can only be what's true
哪怕千金散尽
If all was lost
也是塞翁失马
There's more I gained
因为这让我找回了
Cause it led me back
你
To you
我曾与国王女王畅饮香槟
I drank champagne with kings and queens
被政客溜须吹捧
The politicians praised my name
但那其实是别人的梦想
But those are someone else's dreams
是我因忘本而步入的陷阱
The pitfalls of the man I became
珍妮·林德受到热烈迎接
年复一年
For years and years
我寻求欢呼
I chased their cheers
疯狂向前不停步 不满足
The crazy speed of always needing more
但当我驻足
But when I stop
看到你时
And see you here
才记起这一切本是为了谁
I remember who all this was for
从今后
From now on
我的双眼再不会为金光蒙蔽
These eyes will not be blinded by the lights
从今后
From now on
曾被我推迟的许诺将从今晚开始
What's waited till tomorrow starts tonight
从今晚开始
It starts tonight
我就此许下承诺
Let this promise in me start
宛如心中的圣歌
Like an anthem in my heart
从今后
From now on
我们还能找回初心
And we will come back home
我们还能重回家园
回归家庭
Home, again!
我们还能找回初心
And we will come back home
我们还能重回家园
回归家庭
Home, again!
我们还能找回初心
And we will come back home
我们还能重回家园
回归家庭
Home, again!
从今后
From now on!
我们还能找回初心
And we will come back home
我们还能重回家园
回归家庭
Home, again!
我们还能找回初心
And we will come back home
我们还能重回家园
回归家庭
Home, again!
我们还能找回初心
And we will come back home
我们还能重回家园
没错
Yes!
回归家庭
Home, again!
我们还能找回初心
And we will come back home
我们还能重回家园
回归家庭
Home, again!
从今后
From now on
我的双眼再不会为金光蒙蔽
These eyes will not be blinded by the lights
从今后
From now on
曾被我推迟的许诺将从今晚开始
What's waited till tomorrow starts tonight
从今晚开始
It starts tonight
我就此许下承诺
Let this promise in me start
宛如心中的圣歌
Like an anthem in my heart
从今后
From now on
我们还能找回初心
And we will come back home
我们还能重回家园
回归家庭
Home, again!
我们还能找回初心
And we will come back home
我们还能重回家园
回归家庭
Home, again!
你在这儿
You are here.
从今后
From now on
回归家庭
Home, again!
从今后
From now on
回归家庭
Home, again!
从今后
From now on
回归家庭
Home, again!
卡罗琳
Caroline.
他来了
He's here.
我想见我妻子
I would like to see my wife.
她不在这里
She's not here.
她去海滩了
She's at the beach.
我给你 给我们的家庭带来了苦难
I have brought hardships on you and our family.
你提醒过我
You warned me...
但我没听
and I wouldn't listen.
我只是
I just wanted...
我想成为更了不起的人
I wanted to be more than I was.
我一直只想要我当初爱上的那个男人
I never wanted anything but the man I fell in love with.
我就此许下承诺
Let this promise in me start
宛如心中的圣歌
Like an anthem in my heart
不管宏大 还是渺小
However big, however small
从今后
From now on.
银行拒绝了
The bank said no?
断然拒绝 怎么说都没用
Emphatically. And repeatedly.
我觉得美国不会再有哪家银行
I don't think there is a bank left in the country
会听我哄骗借给我钱了 所以
I can fool into loaning me more money, so...
很抱歉我让你们失望了
I'm really sorry to disappoint you all.
别担心 巴纳姆 我们都习惯了
Don't worry, Barnum. We've gotten used to it by now.
巴纳姆
You know, Barnum,
我当初认识你时
when I first met you
我有继承权
I had an inheritance, claim
城里所有的派对都愿请我去
and an invitation to every party in town.
现在 拜你所赐 那些都不复存在了
And now thanks to you. All that's gone.
只剩下了友谊 爱情
All that's left is this friendship, love
和我热爱的事业
and work that I adore.
你为我的生活带来了欢乐
You brought joy into my life.
- 对我们所有人都是 - 是啊
- Into all our lives. - Hear, hear.
我需要一家肯接受欢乐做抵押的银行
I need a bank who takes joy as collateral.
他们或许不接受
They may not...
但我接受
But I will.
我拥有10%的利润
I own 10% of the show.
我清楚我老板的脾气
Knowing who I was working for,
所以明智地每周去取钱
I had the good sense to take my cut weekly.
菲利普 我不能允许你赌在我身上
Phillip, I can't let you gamble it on me...
你当然能
Sure you can.
别现在又理智起来了
Don't turn sensible on us now.
合伙人
Partners.
五五分成
Fifty fifty.
合伙人
Partners.
问题是
The only thing is...
我不知道我们怎么能买得起大楼
I don't know how we're gonna afford a building.
是啊
Right.
我们不需要楼
Building. We don't need a building.
在曼哈顿投资地产太不明智了
Real estate in Manhattan is a terrible investment.
我可以花点小钱就在码头附近买到地皮
Why, I can get a land down by the docks for almost nothing.
我们只需要一个帐篷
All we need is a tent.
这是最棒的表演
Oh, this is the greatest show
气势汹汹 我们这群场内的叛逆者
Colossal we come these renegades in the ring
曾经迷失 如今加冕马戏之王
Where the lost get found in the crown of the circus king
别再抗拒 它犹如洪流般袭来
Don't fight it, it's coming for you, running at ya
只在乎此刻 不管之后如何
It's only this moment, don't care what comes after
外面是漆黑一片 我想你心里也清楚
It's blinding outside and I think that you know
投降吧 因为你在呼喊 你向往那里
Just surrender 'cause you're calling and you wanna go
那被缤纷灯光笼罩的地方
Where it's covered in all the colored lights
那由流浪儿称雄的地方
Where the runaways are running the night
那不可能变为可能的地方 它让你意乱情迷
Impossible comes true, intoxicating you
这是最棒的表演
Oh, this is the greatest show
我们点亮夜晚 不肯罢休
We light it up, we won't come down
即使太阳升起也无法阻拦我们
And the sun can't stop us now
看着梦境成为现实 它让你情不自禁
Watching it come true, it's taking over you
这是最棒的表演
Oh, this is the greatest show
这里有你渴望的一切
It's everything you ever want
这里有你需要的一切
It's everything you ever need
全部摆在了你面前
And it's here right in front of you
这里就是你向往的地方
This is where you wanna be (this is where you wanna be)
这里有你渴望的一切
It's everything you ever want
这里有你需要的一切
It's everything you ever need
全部摆在了你面前
And it's here right in front of you
这里就是你向往的地方
This is where you wanna be
那被缤纷灯光笼罩的地方
Where it's covered in all the colored lights
那由流浪儿称雄的地方
Where the runaways are running the night
那不可能变为可能的地方 它让你情不自禁
Impossible comes true, it's taking over you
这个给你了
This is for you.
这是最棒的表演
Oh, this is the greatest show
- 那你干什么去 - 看我女儿长大
- What are you going to do? - Watching my girls grow up.
演出还得继续
The show must go on.
我们点亮夜晚 不肯罢休
We light it up, we won't come down
即使太阳升起也无法阻拦我们
And the sun can't stop us now
看着梦境成为现实 它让你情不自禁
Watching it come true, it's taking over you
这是最棒的表演
This is the greatest show
那被缤纷灯光笼罩的地方
Where it's covered in all the colored lights
那由流浪儿称雄的地方
Where the runaways are running the night
那不可能变为可能的地方 它让你情不自禁
Impossible comes true, it's taking over you
这是最棒的表演
Oh, this is the greatest show
我们点亮夜晚 不肯罢休
We light it up, we won't come down
高墙再也无法阻隔我们
And the walls can't stop us now
看着梦境成为现实 它让你情不自禁
I'm watching it come true, it's taking over you
这是最棒的表演
Oh, this is the greatest show
你渴望的一切尽在眼前
'Cause everything you want is right in front of you
你看到不可能变为可能
And you see the impossible is coming true
高墙再也无法阻隔我们
And the walls can't stop us (now) now, yeah
这是最棒的表演
This is the greatest show
爸爸
Daddy.
姑娘们
Hey, girls.
大伙儿让让路
Hello. Make way.
这是最棒的表演
This is the greatest show
这里有你渴望的一切
It's everything you ever want
这里有你需要的一切
It's everything you ever need
全部摆在了你面前
And it's here right in front of you
最高尚的艺术是为他人带来欢乐 —— PT·巴纳姆